Olga Bolshchikova

Product/UX Designer

I am a Product/UX designer with an international background and I4+ years of visual design experience. Through empathy, I create solutions valuable to both users and business. And when designing, I strive to achieve a harmonious blend of functionality and aesthetics.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Visual Designer

BlueApple Design, Menlo Park, CA

Apr 2016-Present

• Collaborated with the creative director to design e-books and white papers to help users better understand the needs and the benefits of the IoT

Product/UX Design Apprentice

Designlab, San Francisco, CA

Jan 2017-Nov 2017

- Conducted user research to reveal insights and gain empathy
- Synthesized findings and formed UX strategy
- Designed UI for responsive websites and mobile apps for iOS and Android
- Conducted usability testing and iterated on design based on feedback
- Helped entrepreneurs stand out from competitors through design their websites

Freelance Visual/UI Designer

Safe Drive Systems, New York, NY

Mar 2015-Mar 2016

- Designed user-centered landing pages, e-brochures, and flyers to solve the company's problems
- Created presentations for potential car buyers in 60+ dealerships which resulted in 18% increase in product sales
- Collaborated with marketing team to redesign the website blog for better user interaction and SEO optimization, increased blog traffic by over 50%

Freelance Graphic Designer

IMR, New York, NY

Sept 2014-Aug 2015

- Executed redesign of the corporate magazine to improve readability
- Implemented image manipulations, photo retouching, and vector graphics to enhance the magazine quality level and visual perception

Sr. Graphic/Web Designer

Integral LLC, Yekaterinburg, Russia

Dec 2000-May 2014

- Participated in all stages of creating 5 scientific magazines and 3 monthly newspapers with a circulation of 25K+; supervised a design process from an idea to production
- Collaborated with developers to improve website UX which directly increased sales by 17%
- Designed ads, posters, brochures, booklets, and presentations to support companies' promotions

http://bolshchikova.com

olga.bolshchikova@gmail.com

(347) 873-7216

San Jose, CA

SKILLS

UX Design

- User Research
- Information Architecture
- Wireframing
- Interaction Design
- UI Design
- Prototyping
- Usability Testing

Visual Design

- Layout
- Typography
- Branding
- Image Manipulation
- Print Production

TOOLS

- Sketch
- Photoshop
- InDesign
- Illustrator
- InVision / Marvel
- Balsamiq / Axure
- Zeplin
- Acrobat
- HTML5 / CSS3
- Keynote / PowerPoint

EDUCATION

UX Academy

DesignLab Nov 2017

• UX/UI Design Fundamentals

Bloc.io Dec 2015

 Bachelor of Science (BS), Engineering Physics

Ural Federal University, Russia

TRAINING

• UX & Web Design Master Course
Udemy

March 2017

• Human-Computer Interaction

Coursera Aug 2014

HTML & CSS

Codecademy May 2013